So then the seventh planet was the Earth.
The Earth is not just an ordinary planet!
One can count; there 111 kings (not forgetting, to be sure, the
Negro kings among them some 7 000 geographers, 900, ,000 businessmen
seven and a half million tipplers 311 million conceited men-- that is to say,
about 2 billion grown-ups.
To give you an idea of the size of Earth, I will tell you that before the
invention of electricity it was necessary to maintain, over the whole of
the six continents, a veritable army of 462, ,511 lamplighters for the street lamps.
Seen from a slight distance, that would make a splendid spectacle. The movements
of this army would be regulated like those of the ballet in the opera.
First would come the term of the lamplighters of New Zealand in Australia.
Having set their lamps alight, these would go off to sleep.
Next, the lamplighters of India China and Siberia would enter for their steps in
the dense and then they too would be waved back into the wings foreign
of the lamplighters of Russia in the Indies; then those of Africa and Europe
than those of South America than those of North America.
And never would they make a mistake in the order of their entry upon the stage.
It would be magnificent.
Only the man who was in charge of the single lamp at the North Pole, and his
colleague who was responsible for the single lamp of the South Pole-- only these
two would live free from toil and care they'd be busy just two times in the whole year